Rockwell Kent papers 4079547
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Rockwell Kent papers
1885-1970
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4079547
59 linear feet 59 linear feet 46 boxes 10 drawers 3 slip cases
A significant collection of Rockwell Kent's correspondence; drawings and sketches; watercolors; lithographs; proofs; manuscripts; and architectural drawings. There are also lithographs and woodblock prints by Kent's students and admirers.
Arrangement
In XV Series: Series I: Cataloged materials: Correspondence, Manuscripts and Prints by Other Artists -- Series II: Cataloged Manuacripts, Prints by others, etc. -- Series III: Titled Drawings, Lithographs, Prints and Proofs -- Series IV: Advertising -- Series V: Architecture -- Series VI: Book Illustration -- Series VII: Bookplates -- Series VIII: Exhibitions -- Series VIX: Magazine Illustrations -- Series X: Posters -- Series XI: Other Categories -- Series XII: Miscellaneous Drafts and Sketches-Early Work -- Series XIII: Miscellaneous Printed Materials -- Series XIV: Articles, Broadside, Clippings, Obituaries, and Photographs -- Series XV: Additions to the Collection.
General Note
Other collections of Rockwell Kent materials are at: SUNY-Plattsburgh (Rockwell Kent Collection); National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution (Peter A. Juley & Son Collection, Photographs); Archives of American Art (Ken Papers); & Princeton University Library (Graphic Arts-Kentiana)
Restrictions on Access
This collection is located on-site.
Restrictions on Access
This collection has no restrictions.
Scope and Content
A comprehensive collection of working drawings and sketches, watercolor paintings, lithographs, proofs, manuscripts, and architectural drawings. There are illustrations for many books including Moby Dick, Beowulf, The Canterbury Tales, The Decameron, Paul Bunyan, Candide, and The Bridge of San Luis Rey, as well as illustrations for 18 of Kent's own books; bookplates for many well known people, magazine illustrations, advertising, posters, and graphic art work of many other types. Some correspondence is included, as well as many lithographs and woodblock prints by Kent's students and admirers.
Acquisition
1971 M-1971 Berol, Mr & Mrs A.C. Gift
11/04/1996 M-96-11-04 31 letters from RK to Henry Wohltjen 6758B(Friends) Purchase
01/31/1997 M-97-01-31 6 RK letters to Art Young 2293B Purchase
02/20/1997 M-97-02-20 RK letter to Art Young 2293B Purchase
05/26/1995 M-95-05-26 Papers 6192B(Mixer), 2293B, 2293X, 6346B(Berg) Purchase
09/18/2013 2013.2014.M075 4 Rockwell Kent letters from David J. Homles Autographs Purchase
Biographical / Historical
American artist, travel writer, and political activist.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Mr & Mrs Alfred C. Berol, Dan Burne Jones, Corliss Lamont& Mrs Arthur Hays Sulzberger, 1971, etc.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Leo Lefkowitz, 1979.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Charles Green & Martianne Reges, 1979.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Gordon Ray, 1986.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Herman Cohen, 1988.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Barry Scott.
Ownership and Custodial History
Gift of Mr & Mrs George Spector.
Art; Drawing; Graphic arts; Illustrated books; Illustration of books; Advertisements; Affidavits; Alphabets; Announcements; Architectural drawings; Articles; Artists' proofs; Book illustrations; Book jackets; Bookplates; Broadsides; Calendars; Calligraphy; Cartoons; Catalogs; Chalk drawings; Charcoal drawings; Decorations; Design drawings; Drawings; Elevations; Exhibition Catalogs; Frontispieces; Greeting cards; Illustrations; Initials; Intaglio prints; Invitations; Labels; Linocuts; Lists; Lithographs; Maps; Menus; Murals; Overlays; Packages; Pastel drawings; Paintings; Periodical illustrations; Pictures; Portraits; Postage stamps; Posters; Prints; Programs; Proofs; Prospectuses; Recipes; Record jackets; Renderings; Self-portraits; Sketches; Stationery; Stencils; Tableware; Textile design drawings; Title pages; Tombstones; Trade cards; Trademarks; Videotapes; Vignettes; Wash drawings; Watercolor drawings; Woodcuts; Wrapping paper; Artists; Authors, Anerican; Cartoonists; Engravers; Illustrators; Lithographers; Painters; Adler, Elmer, 1884-1962; Ahgupuk, George Aden; Cleland, T. M (Thomas Maitland), 1880-1964; Cohen, Herman; Cook, Howard Norton, 1901-1980; Dwight, Mabel, 1876-1955; Floethe, Richard; Gág, Wanda, 1893-1946; I͡Akubov, V. V; IAkutovych, Heorhi; Inescort, Frieda, 1901-1976; Jones, Dan Burne; Kittredge, William A (William Albion), 1891-1945; Kulʹchyt͡sʹka, Olena Lʹvivna, 1877-1967; Kut͡senko, Petro; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995; Lankes, Julius J., 1884-1960; Leighton, Clare, 1898-1989; Lenski, Lois, 1893-1974; Lismer, Arthur, 1885-1969; McGuire, Harry, 1904-; Masyk, Volodymyr, 1917-; Petty, Mary; Price, Art, 1918-; Rosenberg, James N (James Naumburg), 1874-1970; Selivanov, I; Smith, Frank Leon; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985; West, Richard V; Young, Art, 1866-1943
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  In four boxes, numbered 1-4. Kent's letters are arranged chronologically in Boxes 2: (1918-1940); 3: (1941-1969); 4 (Letters to Richard K. Larcada, 1965-1970).
  - Adler, Elmer: to Frances Lee Kent (Mrs. Rockwell), t.l.s, 30 August 1927 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Elmer: to Juliet Koenig Smith, 2 t.l.s. & telegram, & misc., 1932-1937 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Elmer: to Rockwell Kent, t.l.s., 13, June 1934 (Box 1)
  - Ahgupuk, George: to Rockwell Kent from Edith and Ollie Weaver, ink sketch and a.l.s. (Box 1)
  - Arens, Egmont & Ruth: to Rockwell Kent, a.n.s. on New Year card, undated (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Herman: to Frank Leon Smith, 9 February & 24 2 t.1., February1973 (Box 1)
  - Cottington, C.H.: to Rockwell Kent, t.l.s., 10, December 1927 (Box 1)
  - Driscoll, William M.J.: to John Whiting (Box 1)
  - Friel, John Whiting: to Rockwell Kent, t.l.s., 12, March1957 (Box 1)
  - Friel, John Whiting: to Kent, Rockwell, a.l.s., 18, March1957 (Box 1)
  - Hall, R.T.: to Juliet Koenig Smith, 1 t.l.s., 1, May 1936 (Box 1)
  - Herzog, H.: to Hulda Hirsch, 2 a.p.c.s., each includes a drawing (Box 1)
  - Inescort, Frieda: to Kent, Rockwell, a.l.s. on Christmas card, undated (Box 1)
  - Kent, Frances Lee (Mrs. Rockwell): to Juliet Koenig Smith and Frank Leon Smith, 20 t.l.s., 10 a.l.s., telegram and p.c.s., &, 1929-1940; undated (Box 1)
  - Kent, Rockwell: (Box 1)
    - To Kathy, a.l. in verse, undated (Box 1)
    - To Santa Claus, ms.l.s., 7 December, ca. 1885 (Box 1)
    - To Hildegarde Hirsch, 160 a.l.s., 8 a.l., 2 a.p.c.s., & 2 p.p.c. (St. Valentine's Day cards) [1916-1917] &, undated (Box 1)
    - To Hildegarde Hirsch, 160 a.l.s., 8 a.l., 2 a.p.c.s., & 2 p.p.c. (St. Valentine's Day cards) [1918-1921] &, undated (Box 2)
    - To Miss Köhler, a.l.s. [1916] (Box 1)
    - To Frieda Hirsch, a.l.s. 23, September 1918 (Box 2)
    - To Henry Wohltjen, 10 a.l.s., 20 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 1919-1940 (Box 2)
    - To Henry Wohltjen, 10 a.l.s., 20 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 1941-1946 (Box 2)
    - To L.M. Olson, a.l.s., 31 Oct, 1919 (Box 2)
    - To Ernesta Drinker Bullitt Beaux Barlow (Mrs Samuel L.M.), 30 a.l.s., 1 a.l., November -December 1924 (Box 2)
    - To Juliet Koenig Smith, 2 a.l.s. [December 1927 À] & (Box 2)
    - To Charles Boni, Jr., a.l.s., 12, July 1928 (Box 2)
    - To to Juliet Koenig Smith and Frank Leon Smith, 47 t.l.s., t.l. 19 a.l.s., a.l., p.c.s. & 6 telegrams, &, 1929-1940; undated (Box 2)
    - To to Juliet Koenig Smith and Frank Leon Smith, 47 t.l.s., t.l. 19 a.l.s., a.l., p.c.s. & 6 telegrams, &, 1941-1961; undated (Box 3)
    - To Albert Boni, 1 a.l.s., 2 t.l.s., May 1930 (Box 2)
    - To Leonard Levinson, 10 letters (dating 1941-1942) (Box 3)
    - To Rose Ornstein, 2 t.l.s., June -July 1930 (Box 2)
    - To Art Young, 1 a.l.s., 5 t.l.s., 1 t.l., &, 1936-1949; undated (Box 2)
    - To Art Young, 1 a.l.s., 5 t.l.s., 1 t.l., &, 1941-1943; undated (Box 3)
    - To Guido Reinhardt Rahr, a.l.s., ca. 1946 (Box 3)
    - To Ned, 5 t.l.s., Jan-Feb, 1950 (Box 3)
    - To Harold Witter Bynner, t.l.s., 20 Jan, 1962 (Box 3)
    - To Richard K. Larcada, 106 t.l.s., 2 a.p.c.s., 2 t.l. (carbon), 1965-1970 (Box 4)
    - To Joanne Watson, t.l.s., 16 March 1965 (Box 3)
    - To Frank Tornabene, t.l. (carbon), 8 January 1966 (Box 3)
    - To Marion Hinrichs, t.l. (carbon), 18 June 1966 (Box 3)
    - To Vladimir Semenovich Kemenov, t.l.s. (photocopy), 24 June 1966 (Box 3)
    - To Anatoli Nikolaievich Krutikov, t.l.s. (photocopy), 24, June 1966 (Box 3)
    - To Maria Yedovina, t.l.s. (photocopy), 24, June 1966 (Box 3)
    - To Mrs. J.S. Johnson, t.l. (carbon), 16, November 1966 (Box 3)
    - To Herman Cohen, t.l.s., 24, February1967 (Box 3)
    - To Richard Morford, t.l. (carbon), ca. 15 Feb. 1968 (Box 3)
    - To Ekaterina Alekseevn Furtseva, t.l. (carbon), 8, February1969 (Box 3)
  - Kittredge, William A.: t.l.s. to Rockwell Kent, 22 October 1930 (Box 3)
  - Laury, Helen: to Juliet Koenig Smith, t.l.s., 17, April 1931 (Box 3)
  - McGuire, Harry: to Rockwell Kent, t.l.s., undated (Box 3)
  - Price, Arthur: to Rockwell Kent, t.l.s., 15, December 1942 (Box 3)
  - Pynson Printers, Inc.: to Rockwell Kent, t.l., 13, December 1927 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Frank Leon: to Herman Cohen, 1 Feb to 15 3 t.l.s., 1973; July 1973 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Juliet Koenig:
    - To Elmer Adler, a.l.s., undated (Box 3)
    - To Herman Cohen, 4 t.l.s., 1 a.n.s., 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Wiesenberger, Arthur: to Rockwell Kent, a.l.s., undated (Box 3)
- Series II: Cataloged Manuacripts, Prints by others, etc.
  - Ahgupuk, George Twok Aden, [Two Eskimos fishing] (Ink sketch, Signed, N. p., [1935]. 5-1/2 x 4-1/4), 1911-2001 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Black Horse Square, Lisbon (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 1956. 11 x 8) (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Boat at Viera, Portugal (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 1956. 10-1/2 x 8) (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Leiria (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 1956. 11 x 8-3/4) (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Leiria (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 1956. 7-1/2 x 11-1/2) (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Leiria (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 1956. 10.5 x 15.5) (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Caplan, David: Lisbon, waterfront (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 9 x 10-1/2), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Lottery ticket seller, Lisbon (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 11-1/4 x 8), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Nazaré (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 11-1/4 x 6-1/2), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Nazaré (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 10-1/2 x 6-1/2), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: Nazaré (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., (11" x 15.5"), 1956 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Caplan, David: Nets drying at Viera (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 11 x 7), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: On the Tagus (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 10-1/2 x 8), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: On the Tagus (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 11-1/2 x 7), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: On the train to Sintra (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 11 x 7-1/4), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Caplan, David: River Tagus (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 10-1/2 x 7-3/4), 1956 (Box 5)
  - Cleland, Thomas Maitland. [The advertising man]. Aquatint, (8" x 10.5"), 1929 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Cleland, Thomas Maitland. Lettering A.ms. (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Cook, Howard, [Cityscape] (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Rockwell Kent, N. p., N. d., 5 x 12), 1901-1980 (Box 5)
  - Daichetov(?), [Untitle engraving] (10.5" x 13.5"), 1956 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Dwight, Mabel. Basque country,. Lithograph (13" x 10"), 1927 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Floethe, Richard, [Seated girl] (Woodblock, print in colors, Signed, N. p., N. d., 7-3/4 x 10-1/4), 1901-1988 (Box 5)
  - Floethe, Richard. [Farmyard],. Woodblock print (10.5" x 8.5"), 1935 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Gag, Wanda Hazel, A merry Christmas (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Frances and Rockwell Kent, N. p., 5-3/4 x 4-1/2), 1893-1946; 1928 (Box 5)
  - Gag, Wanda Hazel. [Spinning wheel], lithograph, (10.75" x 9"), 1893-1946 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Grant-Ford, Maud: [English village] (Woodblock print,, N. p., N. d., 6 x 8) (Box 5)
  - Hirai, Bokuyo, [Fishing scene] (Woodblock, print in colors, N. p., N. d., 12 x 8), 1608-1678 (Box 5)
  - Iakubov, V. V.: Untitled (Woodblock print,, Signed, S. n., 5-3/4 x 9-1/4), 1958 (Box 5)
  - Jones, Dan Burne: The dream keeper, lithograph, 1929 (9.5" x 9.5") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Jones, Dan Burne: Rockwellkentiana: printed bookplate made for Rockwell Kent, Bookplate) (Box 5)
  - Katsukawa, Shunzan (fl. late 18th century): Buddah's birthday festival, woodblock print, (13.5" x 10.5") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Rockwell Kent (1858-1934): "In Excuse", t.ms., 128p. (Box 5)
    Mimeographed volume of poetry, bound copy, #6 of 10 copies, inscribed to his sister Charlotte. This Rockwell Kent is not related to R. Kent (1882-1971).
  - Rockwell Kent (1858-1934): "July 18" and other poems, t.ms., 84p. (Box 5)
    This Rockwell Kent is not related to R. Kent (1882-1971).
  - Rockwell Kent (1858-1934): King Street, (Lithograph, 16.5 x 14cm) (Box 5)
  - Kent, Rockwell:
    - Diary Notes & poems, a.ms., 39 p. (Box 5)
    - "God bless my love and hear my prayer...", a.ms. poem (Box 5)
    - "Greetings Frances short and snappy...", a.ms. poem (Box 5)
    - "Eeny, meeny, miney, mo...", Valentine card, a.ms. (Box 5)
    - "Here's happiness", a.ms. recipe (Box 5)
    - "Notes on perspective in drawing bridge", a.ms., 1p. (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
    - "Poor little book...", a.ms.s. book inscription (Box 5)
    - "The girl that I love has eyes of blue...", a.ms. poem (Box 5)
    - "The limbs of a lady named Hanne...", a.ms. poem (Box 5)
    - "This rosy cheeked beauty...", a.ms. poem (Box 5)
    - "You loved that melody...", t.ms. poem (Box 5)
  - Kent, Sally (Mrs. Rockwell): "Asgaard destroyed"-April 19, 1969. t.ms. (with ms corrections in the hand of Rockwell Kent). (Box 5)
  - Kul'chitskaia, Eleana Livovna. Khata v Karpatatyakh. Woodblock print, (11.5" x 9.5") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Kutsenko, Petro. Rannaia zima, 1947. Woodblock print, (7" x 11.5") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Lakutovich, Georgii. Boian vieshchii..., Woodblock print, (9" x 14.25") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Buddy Lankes his book: bookplate (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., 3-1/4 x 3-3/4), 1884-1960; 1920 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Buffalo Harbor (Woodblock print,, N. p., N. d., 9-1/4 x 12-1/2), 1884-1960 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Christmas card] (Woodblock print,, N. p., N. d., 3-1/2 x 5), 1884-1960 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Church] (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., 6-1/4 x 4-1/4), 1884-1960; 1920 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Cider Mill I (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Rockwell Kent, N. p., 10 x 8), 1884-1960; 1922 (Mapcase 13V-F01)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Cider Mill II (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Rockwell Kent, N. p., 10-1/4 x 8-1/4), 1884-1960; 1922 (Mapcase 13V-F01)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Classical facade] (Woodblock print,, With note in the artist's hand, N. p., N. d., 3-3/4 x 4-1/4), 1884-1960 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Farmhouse] (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Rockwell Kent, N. p., 5-3/4 x 5), 1884-1960; 1923 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., The hired man's house (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Frances Kent, N. p., 9-1/2 x 7), 1884-1960; 1929 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Indian summer (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Rockwell Kent, N. p., 8-1/4 x 6), 1884-1960; 1922 (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Kent's gate (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., 8-3/4 x 6-1/2), 1884-1960; 1930 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Laborer] (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., 4-1/4 x 2-3/4), 1884-1960; 1917 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., The meeting house (Woodblock print,, Signed, S. n., 8-1/2 x 6-1/2), 1884-1960; 1919 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Mill Race Road (Woodblock print,, With note in artist's hand, S. n., N. d., 7-3/4 x 5-3/4), 1884-1960 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Mushrooms] (Woodblock print,, Signed, S. n., 4 x 2-3/4), 1884-1960; 1918 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Old house in Georgetown (Woodblock print,, Signed; inscribed to Rockwell Kent, S. n., 6-1/4 x 8-3/4), 1884-1960; 1923 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Peanut man (Woodblock print,, S. n., N. d., 10 x 8-3/4), 1884-1960 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Saint Mary's Inn (Woodblock print,, Signed, S. n., 10 x 8), 1884-1960; 1920 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., The tavern (Woodblock print,, S. n., 10-3/4 x 8), 1884-1960; 1919 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., [Two ships] (Woodblock print,, Signed, S. n., 6 x 4), 1884-1960; 1920 (Box 5)
  - Lankes, Julius J., Winter (Woodblock print,, S. n., 10 x 7), 1884-1960; 1921 (Box 5)
  - Leighton, Clare, Genoa (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., N. d., 9-1/4 x 7), ca. 1901-1989 (Box 5)
  - Leighton, Clare, Threshing (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., N. d., 5-1/2 x 7-1/2), ca. 1901-1989 (Box 5)
  - Lenski, Lois, Toward the sea (Woodblock print,, Signed, N. p., N. d. 6 x 6), 1893-1974 (Box 5)
  - Lismer, Arthur, The Arctic medal-presented by the Gov.-Gen. of Can. (Cartoon of Rockwell Kent--Ink sketch, N. p., Ca. 1934. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.), 1885-1969 (Box 5)
  - Masyk, Voldymyr. Old man. Woodblock print, (20.5" x 22.5") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Negalesco, Jean. Two figures. Ink sketch, (10.5" x 8") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Pascheret, Léon René, [Barn] (Engraving, Signed, N. p., 1933. 8 x 6-1/2), 1892-1971 (Box 5)
  - Peirce, Gerry, Church at Tubac (Engraving, Signed, N. p., N. d. 7-1/2 x 6), 1900-1969 (Box 5)
  - Petty, Mary. For God so loved the world. Lithograph, (11.5" x 10") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Rosenberg, James N. Nov. 13 mad house 1929. Lithograph, (9.5" x 15.5") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Selivanov, T. Kiev. Risunki Uspenskogo Sobora. Woodblock print, (12.5" x 11") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Tulkatceff, Zinovii (À): Fleurs doswlecim (Lithograph, Signed, N. p., 1946. 6-1/4 x 10-1/4) (Box 5)
  - Underwood, Leon A., [Noah's ark] (Woodblock print, Signed, N. p., 1926. 6-3/4 x 7-3/4), 1890-1975 (Box 5)
  - Ward, Lynd Kendall, Bookplate made for Dan Burne Jones (Bookplate, N. p., N. d.), 1905-1985 (Box 5)
  - Zutyrents, G. Untitled. Woodblock print, (12.25" x 8") (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
  - Printed misc: Ooaizer, G.M., S.K. Folomkina and E.I. Kaar. English; oochebnik angliiskogo yazeka dlya ch klassa srednei shkole...Moscow, Prosveshchenie, 1966, 206 pages (Box 5)
    10th form English reader, with articles on R.K.: p. 47-50.
  - Miscellaneous, 30 pages (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 5 items (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 pages (Mapcase 13V-F-01)
- Series III: Titled Drawings, Lithographs, Prints and Proofs
  - Adventure: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Afternoon at sea; clipping (Box 6)
  - Alaska painting; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Almost; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - pencil sketch (Box 6)
  - And women must weep; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - The apprentice; pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 6)
  - The Arctic Medal-presented by the Gov. Gen. of Canada; ink sketch (see: cataloged materials by other artists: Arthur Lismer, p.3) (Box 6)
  - Art and the child; proof (Box 6)
  - Art and the child; proof with ink wash (Box 6)
  - Art and the child; proof with ink wash (draft) (Box 6)
  - August twenty-third (Sacco and Vanzetti); wood engraving on maple (Box 6)
  - Barney Roos Jeep; pencil draft Bather; proof and printed copy Beowulf: See: Book illus.: Beowulf (Box 6)
  - Beowulf & dragon: See: Book illus.: Beowulf
  - Beowulf and Grendal's mother; oversize lithograph (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - see also: Book illus.: Beowulf
  - A birthday book: See: Book illus.: Kent: A birthday book
  - Blue bird: See: Book illus.: De Lima, Agnes
  - Bon voyage; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Bowsprit; photo of printed copy (Box 6)
  - Bringing home the Christmas tree; pencil drafts, 5 p. (Box 6)
  - The burial; pencil and charcoal draft (Box 6)
  - The cabin window: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness (Box 6)
  - Cain: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Central Park, ca. 1907. Pencil sketch, 3 3/4 x 6 inches. (oversize) (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Charity; ink and pencil drafts (Box 6)
  - Child and lamb: See: Art and the child
  - Child and star; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Christmas tree; linoleum block print (incomplete) (Box 6)
  - Clara: See: Portrait of a child
  - Climbing the bars; pencil sketch (Box 6)
  - The clinic; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Day: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Day's end: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - The day's work: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Deep water; pencil draft and proof (Box 6)
  - Dick Worrell's cabin; oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Dirty Deborah: See: Book illus.: Kent: Greenland Journal
  - The diver; oversize ink and pencil drafts (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - oversize pencil drafts, 2p. (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Driftwood; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Ecstasy: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Enormous new machines make men master over nature; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Europe (seated figure); pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 6)
  - Fair wind; oversize wood engraving (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - The faller:
    - pencil draft (Box 6)
    - oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - pencil sketch (Box 6)
    - oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Far horizon:
    - pencil draft (Box 6)
    - pencil sketch (Box 6)
  - Farewell: See: Book illus.: Robinson, Selma: City child -- frontspiece
  - Fire!:
    - pencil drafts, 3p. (Box 6)
    - See also: Posters: Forest Fire Fighters Service
  - Fire wood: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Flame; pencil draft (Box 6)
  - Foot bath: See Susanna
  - Foreboding: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Forest pool; oversize pencil draft (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Fox Island, Resurrection Bay...: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - France & Rhine (sketches):
    - ink & pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 6)
    - __ink drafts, 3p. (Box 6)
    - __pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 6)
    - __pencil sketches, 4p. (Box 6)
  - Frozen fall: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Funeral pyre:
    - oversize lithograph (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - See also: Book illus.: Beowulf
  - Genealogical tree:
    - oversize lithograph (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - See also: Book illus.: Beowulf
  - Get up: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Girl on cliff:
    - pencil draft (Box 6)
    - proof (Box 6)
  - Gladys Loftus; pencil sketch (Box 6)
  - Glory, glory, hallelujah:
    - pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 6)
    - pencil and litho crayon sketch (oversize) (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
  - Go to bed: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Good-by: See: Book illus.: Kent: Greenland journal
  - Good-bye day; pencil drafts, 4p. (Box 6)
  - Greenland girl:
    - See: Book illus.: Kent: A Greenland letter -- preface
    - See also: Book illus.: Beowulf-a title page illus. Greenland landscape: See: Book illus.: Kent: A Greenland letter -- preface
  - Greenland sketches:
    - ink sketches, 2p. (Box 6)
    - pencil drafts, 11p. (Box 6)
  - Greenland swimmer; pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 6)
  - Hail and farewell: See: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)
  - Harvester: See: Advertising: Junior art patrons of America.
  - Harvesters, 1935. pen and ink on paper, 10 x 13 1/2 inches. (Larcarda cat. no. 62) (Box 6)
  - The hermit: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Hero: See: Bookplate: Avery, George Edwin
  - Home building: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - Homeport:
    - pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 6)
    - photo of printed copy (Box 6)
    - See also: Book illus.: Kent: N by E (Random House)
  - Imminence: See: Book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - The imperishable: See: book illus.: Kent: Wilderness
  - In the year of Our Lord: See: Book illus.: Kent: This is my own-p.341
  - International Workers Order:
    - oversize crayon & pencil sketch (Box 6)
    - oversize pencil sketch (Mapcase 13V-F-02)
    - pencil drafts, 5p. (Box 6)
    - (unused version); pencil drafts, 2p. (Box 6)
    - pencil sketch (Box 6)
  - Ireland (sketches):
    - ink & pencil drafts (Box 6)
    - pencil drafts, 20p. (Box 6)